Jonathon Misner

Chicago, IL 60611 (520) 548-1536

jonmisner86@gmail.com

https://github.com/JonMisner | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathon-misner-93395b40 https://jonmisnerportfolio.herokuapp.com

Summary:

A fresh full stack developer, I'm ready to create and develop a stunning UX in web applications. I studied at Northwestern University where I gained skills in several different web development technologies, with an emphasis on MERN. My background is in the Service Industry (with my passion being wine and cocktails) and I can bring that work ethic over with me to this new field. With an emphasis on mobile friendly and responsive designs, my goal is to provide polished, sleek, and engaging web applications. Furthermore, I strive to make the UI approachable, and intuitively easy to use for even novice users. Group projects have been a highlight of my coding experience, and I look forward to collaborating with other talented developers and engineers.

Projects:

Informed Trades https://github.com/JonMisner/Informed_Trades https://joolyen.github.io/Informed_Trades

- A web app that combines APIs for stocks and the New York Times to give investors up to date news about the companies they are looking to invest in.
- Primarily responsible for the HTML and CSS, and assisted in the javascript and API calls.
- Used Bulma CDN for the basic design, HTML, CSS, Javascript and JQuery, Google Fonts, AphaVantage API, and the New York Times API.

FitUp | https://github.com/JonMisner/FitUp | http://project-two-2020.herokuapp.com

- A web app for finding exercises and creating custom workouts. Also integrates google maps to find nearby gyms or parks depending on whether you want to focus on indoor or outdoor exercises.
- Primarily responsible for the login page (using Passport and Bcrypt), and used my front end skills to assist in the overall design of the app.
- Used Bootstrap CDN for basic design, HTML, CSS, Passport.js, Bcrypt, Express, Node, Mysql, Sequelize, Handlebars, Google Maps, and more.

Budget Tracker | https://github.com/JonMisner/pwaBudgetTracker | https://jm-budget-tracker.herokuapp.com

- A PWA used for creating and tracking a budget either online or offline
- Responsible for the creation of the service worker and other offline functionality.
- Used Express, Morgan, indexDB, Javascript, CSS, HTML.

Education:

Northwestern University

Evanston, IL

Studied: Full Stack Web Development (certificate)

The University of Arizona

Tucson, AZ Studied:

- History
- Political Science

Technical Skills:

Languages: HTML, Javascript, JQuery, ES6, CSS

Frameworks &CDNs: React, Node, Bootstrap, Bulma, Foundation

APIs: Alphavantage, Googlemaps, New York Times, OMDB

NPMs: Express, Passport, Bcrypt, Morgan, Handlebars, Reactstrap

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, IndexDB, Local Storage

Repos and Deployment: GitHub, GitLab, Heroku

Work Experience:

Bartender:

Sept. 2017 – December 2018 Untitled Supper Club

Chicago, II - (312) 880-1501

Tucson, Az - (520) 579-2100

Manager & Sommelier:

October 2016 – Sept. 2017 The Hampton Social

Chicago, II - (312) 464-0500

January 2015 – Oct. 2016
. Japonais by Morimoto
Chicago, II - (312) 822-9600

July 2012 – Dec. 2014 Bistrot Margo

Chicago, II - (312) 587-3660

November 2010 – Dec. 2011 McClintock's